(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Cat♥Hoodie
ゲスト多数出演！
すーぱー告知もあり！
おかゆ生誕祭 2024
BIRTHDAY 3D LIVE
Cat♥Hoodie
Featuring many guests!
Super announcement too!
Okayu Birthday Festival 2024
BIRTHDAY 3D LIVE
Cat♥Hoodie 2024 BIRTHDAY 3D LIVE
NEKOMATA OKAYU 2024 BIRTHDAY LIVE
OKAYU
驚くくらい
It's surprising
はぁー、はい。
Haa, okay.
はーい、皆さん、こんばんはー！
Hi everyone, good evening!
本日、猫又おかゆバースデー3Dライブ2024、Cat♥Hoodieへようこそー！
Welcome to Nekomata Okayu Birthday 3D Live 2024, Cat♥Hoodie!
こちらハッシュタグ、#猫又おかゆ生誕祭2024 でたくさんポストしてね。
Please post a lot using the hashtag #NekomataOkayuBirthday2024.
早速ですが、1曲目「プラチナ」歌わせていただきました。
To start things off, I just sang the first song, "Platina."
この曲はもう何と言ってもね、忙しい時にたくさん元気と勇気をもらっていた曲になっています。
This song, well, it's one that gave me a lot of energy and courage during busy times.
いっぱい感慨深いなと思いながら歌って踊らせていただきました。
I sang and danced to it while feeling quite deeply moved.
ていうか、このステージさ、見て。すごくなーい？
I mean, look at this stage. Isn't it amazing?
すごくなーい？すごくなーい？
Isn't it amazing? Isn't it amazing?
いやマジですごいんだよ。いや、このステージ可愛くてすごいだけじゃなくて...
No, it's seriously amazing. It's not just cute and amazing...
後になったらこのステージの何がすごいのか、ライブが終わる頃にわかる仕掛けとなっておりますので...
There's actually a secret to what makes this stage so great that you'll understand by the end of the live...
そちらも楽しみにしててください。一旦はこのステージ可愛いなって感じでこのライブ楽しんでいただければなと思います。
So please look forward to that too. For now, I hope you enjoy the live while thinking about how cute the stage is.
ちょっとね、含みもあるんですよ。含みといえば、
There's a little bit of a hint there. Speaking of hints,
今回のライブのタイトルは「Cat♥Hoodie」というタイトルになっておりまして、
The title of this live is "Cat♥Hoodie,"
こちらもいっぱい、いっぱい頭を練って練って練って思いついたタイトルになってるので、
and it's a title I came up with after thinking and thinking and thinking about it a lot,
このライブのタイトルにもどんな意味があるのかな、とか考えながら見てくれると2倍3倍楽しんでいただけるんじゃないかなって思います。
so if you watch while wondering what the meaning of the title is, you might enjoy it two or three times as much.
ここから1時間楽しいこと盛りだくさんだから、みんな乗り遅れるなよー！
There's going to be tons of fun stuff over the next hour, so don't get left behind!
おっ、ゲストのみんなの準備も済んだみたいだよ。
Oh, it looks like all the guests are ready.
それじゃあ、引き続き僕のライブ楽しんでね。行ってきまーす！
Well then, please continue to enjoy my live. Here I go!
Smile! Sweet! Sister! Sadistic! Surprise! Service! We are Stile!!
ぼなぺてぃーと♡S
作詞：こだまさおり 作曲：y0c1e
Bon Appétit ♡ S
Lyrics: Saori Kodama / Composition: y0c1e
さあ 扉を開けて
Now, open the door
未知なるパラダイス
To an unknown paradise
体験しよう おいで おいで
Let's experience it, come on, come on
そう キミを待つのは 不思議なオアシス
Yes, what awaits you is a mysterious oasis
ほっこり日常に ちょっぴり Spice
A little spice for your warm daily life
くるん くるん かきまぜちゃうんだ
Swirl, swirl, we're mixing it all up
くるん くるん 当店自慢のフレーバー
Swirl, swirl, our shop's specialty flavor
サービス サービス ご褒美タイム
Service, service, reward time
おもてなし ココロ込めて
Hospitality with all our heart
Welcome to わい！ わたしたちと一緒に
Welcome to "Why!" Join us
めくるめくワンダーステージ
On this dazzling wonder stage
愛情マシマシ 煩悩ナデナデ
Extra affection, petting away worldly desires
誠心誠意つとめます
We'll serve you with all our heart
イエス！ キミの元気チャージに 一役買えるかな
Yes! Can we play a part in recharging your energy?
ふーりった感じも
Even a cold vibe...
あーりった感じも
...or a warm vibe...
意外と 悪くないでしょ？
...isn't so bad, right?
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい！
Buono Buono, I want to blend!
お口にあいますか？
Is it to your liking?
お口にあうといいな
I hope it's to your liking
ぼなぺてぃーと
Bon Appétit
千客万来！
Business is booming!
ちょっと、なんか、不本意ながらも
Even if it's a bit against my will
いつだって需要は斜め上
Demand is always unexpected
そんじゃ、いっか、ホントのわたしは
Well, then, okay, my true self is...
シークレットモードで 営業スイッチ
...on in secret mode, flipping the business switch
オン！ くるん くるん かきまぜてもっと
On! Swirl, swirl, mix it even more
くるん くるん キミ仕様のフレーバー
Swirl, swirl, a flavor customized for you
サービス サービス 極上タイム
Service, service, premium time
癒やしとは かくあるべき
This is how healing should be
Welcome to わい！ わたし達のお店に 本日もようこそ
Welcome to "Why!" Welcome to our shop today too
おかえり待ってたよ リピートうれしいな 店員一同 歓迎
We've been waiting for you to come home, so glad you're back! A warm welcome from all the staff
いぇーす！
Yes!
君の お疲れ様に
With a recipe perfect
ピッタリのレシピで
for your hard work,
こーゆうのどうかな？
how about something like this?
あーゆうのアリかな？
Is that kind of thing okay?
よろこんでもらえてるかな？
I wonder if you're enjoying it?
Smile!
Sweet!
Sister!
Sadistic!
Small!
Strange!
Serious!
Selfish!
Secret!
Super Girl!
We are スティール!!
We are STILE!!
さあ 扉を開けて 愉快なパラダイス
Come, open the door to a pleasant paradise.
怖がらずにおいで
Don't be afraid, come on in.
そう いつも通りの毎日に
Yes, to your usual everyday,
イロドリと遊び心 召し上がれ
have a taste of color and playfulness.
ブレンド・S
Blend S.
Welcome to...
わーし！ 私達と一緒に
Wow! Join us for
めくるめくワンダーデイジー
a dazzling Wonder Day-zy.
愛情マシマシ 煩悩ナデナデ
Extra love, petting your desires,
誠心誠意つとめます
we'll serve you with all our heart.
いぇーす！
Yes!
君の 元気チャージに ひと役買えるかな
I wonder if I can help recharge your energy.
こーんな感じも あーんま感じも
This kind of feeling, that kind of feeling,
意外と悪くないでしょ？
it's not so bad, is it?
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい
Buono, buono, I want to blend.
君にキュンキュンキュン ハートにパンチパンチパンチ
Kyun-kyun-kyun for you, punch-punch-punch to your heart!
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい
Buono, buono, I want to blend.
お口にあいますか？
Is it to your liking?
お好み聞かせてね
Tell me what you like.
お口にあうといいな
I hope it's to your taste!
社長、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
President, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
いやー泥刑社員集合嬉しすぎるよ
I'm so happy the Doro-Kei employees are all together!
ありがとう、おめでとうおかゆさん
Thank you! Happy birthday, Okayu-san!
今日は特別に我輩たちがプレゼントを用意しました
We've prepared a special present for today.
え、なに？
Oh, what is it?
え、今日ですね、私たち一人一人がなんと
Well, today, each and every one of us...
社長の妹になることになりました！
will become the President's little sister!
妹！？
Little sister!?
ま、ちょっと恥ずかしいけど、社長は物より
It's a bit embarrassing, but I thought you'd enjoy
こういうシチュエーションの方が喜ぶんじゃないかなっていう
this situation more than a physical gift.
正解すぎるけど
You're spot on.
喜んでる
She's loving it.
はいはい、じゃあこん中から誰にやってくれる？
Alright, who's going first?
我にまかせろ
Leave it to me.
じゃあ、先陣を切って
Then, to start us off...
じゃあ、妹になりたい人ここにきてください
Okay, whoever wants to be the sister, step forward.
おかゆお姉ちゃん
Okayu-onee-chan.
何してたの？ どこ行ってたの？
What were you doing? Where were you?
他の人間の匂いがするよ
You smell like other people.
消毒しないとね
We need to disinfect you.
お風呂に入ろ 一緒にお風呂
Let's get in the bath. Together.
かわいい！嬉しい嬉しいありがとう！
Cute! I'm so happy! Thank you!
わー病んでる系妹だ！
Wow, a yandere-type sister!
次誰、次誰
Who's next? Who's next?
我輩ですけど
It's my turn.
妹は嫌だ！
I don't want to be a little sister!
え、何になってくれるのじゃあ
Then what will you be?
おい馬鹿姉貴！
Hey, stupid sister!
誕生日なのいつまで寝てんだよ
It's your birthday, how long are you gonna sleep?
お前、誕生日おめでとうな
Happy birthday, I guess.
あーかわいい！
Cute!
思春期だけど誕生日祝ってくれる弟だ！
A rebellious brother wishing me a happy birthday!
次は誰なんだろう
I wonder who's next.
本物の妹だ！
It's a real little sister!
うちらが偽物みたいに言うなよ
Don't make it sound like we're fakes.
誕生日おめでとう
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！プレゼント！
Thank you! A present!
あーかわいい！
Cute!
なんか年末の先輩でありながら自分の妹にするっていう
The taboo feeling of making your senior colleague
背徳感がね、いいですよね
your sister is great, isn't it?
次は誰なんだい
Who's next?
はい、いつもママなミオちゃんだ
Yes, it's Mio-chan, who's usually the mom.
おねえちゃん
Big sister.
えーっと、あの、いつも、うちのこと、
Um... Big sister...
でも、もっと構ってほしいな
I want you to pay more attention to me.
あーかわいい！ 構ってあげるよ！ お姉ちゃーん！
Cute! I'll give you all the attention! Big sister!
なんかテンション高くね？ 我々の時とテンション違くない？
Wait, isn't your energy way higher than when it was us?
やっぱちょっと甘えたかったんだなっていう、実はね。
Turns out she actually wanted to be pampered.
ママ系妹でした最高です
A mom-type sister, that's the best.
この流れで最後に
And finally, to wrap this up...
大トリの鷹が来ました
The grand finale hawk is here!
やめて待って、もっとハードルを低くして！
Stop, wait! Don't set the bar so high!
妹どこかな
I wonder where my sister is.
お姉ちゃん、早く起きてよ。
Big sister, wake up!
おでんできたよ、おでん
The oden is ready!
おでんで釣っちゃだめ！
Don't bait me with oden!
もっと甘えて！ やり直して！
Be more clingy! Do it over!
リクエストが強すぎるんじゃないか
Your requests are a bit too much.
お姉ちゃん、大好き
Big sister... I love you.
あーかわいい！ 妹きたー！
Ah, cute! There's the little sister!
恥ずかしい！
How embarrassing!
恥ずかしい〜
So embarrassing~
あら可愛い
Oh, how cute
あ〜〜〜凄え！！
Aaah, amazing!!
生まれてこれたことに...
To having been born...
乾杯！
Cheers!
はい、解散！
Okay, dismissed!
解散！解散！解散！
Dismissed! Dismissed! Dismissed!
絶妙に気持ち悪かったね。
That was exquisitely creepy.
何なんだ今のは。
What was that just now?
マジで一人でいいだろ。
I should really just be alone.
待って。退化...
Wait. Regression...
けーたいみしてよ
作詞・作曲：はしメロ
K-Tai Misiteyo
Lyrics & Composition: Hashimero
待ち侘びている大通り
On the main street I've been waiting for
目眩しそうな人混み
In a dizzying crowd
くるり回った昼帯
The midday hour has come around
立ち止まってる　坊　坊
Standing still, kid, kid
しまい切れてない表情
Expression that can't be hidden
どこ見てるの　坊　坊
Where are you looking, kid, kid
知らない
I don't know
今何？
What's now?
目と目止まった合図
Signals where eyes met and stopped
ローリーズ　ロングの
Low-rise, long...
「あとでね」
"Later"
黒文字
Black letters
隠しても無駄ね
It's useless to hide it
けーたいみしてよ今から
Let me see your phone, right now
拒んでるの予想通り
Refusing, just as expected
だって賭けたこの試み
Because I bet on this attempt
くるり回った昼帯
The midday hour has come around
立ち止まっていないで
Don't just stand there
怒ったりしないでよ
Don't get angry
I need チュチュチュチャ
I need chu-chu-chu-cha
いらない
Don't need it
使い古しの愛も
Worn-out love and...
言い訳たちも
all those excuses too
画面じゃなく
Not the screen,
ここ見て
look here
取り上げるからね
I'm taking it away
けーたいみしてよ今から
Let me see your phone, right now
Lonely　ロリロリ神・降臨
Lonely loli-loli god descends
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
If the bell rings, it's just like this
これは救済のレクイエム
This is a requiem of salvation
せーの！　触ったら逮捕！
One-two! Touch and you're arrested!
極chu♡で点呼！
Roll call in prison!
いちー　にー　さん　しー
One, two, three, four
は？　ごめんなさいが聞こえなーい
Huh? I can't hear your apology
粛聖！！　ロリ神レクイエム☆
Punishment!! Loli-God Requiem☆
将来はお前なんかに
In the future, by someone like you
好きかれたくない
I don't want to be liked
泥水で口を洗え
Wash your mouth with muddy water
法廷で会おう？　ねっ
See you in court, okay?
おまわりさん　連れていって
Police officer, take them away
妄想しか取り柄のない
Nothing but delusions...
かわいそうな人
Poor soul
しぃちゃん！しぃちゃん！
Shii-chan! Shii-chan!
その姿　親に見せられますかぁ？
Can you show that figure to your parents?
あみやちゃん！あみやちゃん！
Amiya-chan! Amiya-chan!
うわ、ありがとう　お疲れ様でーす
Ugh, thanks. Good work.
ロリロリ神・降臨
Loli-loli god descends
奴等に用心
Beware of those guys
まともじゃないなら　早く消えてください
If you're not sane, please disappear quickly
ロリロリ神・降臨
Loli-loli god descends
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
If the bell rings, it's just like this
とても優しくて
Very kind and...
素敵なお兄ちゃん
...wonderful big brother
楽園でほら
See, in paradise,
ねんねしな
go to sleep
ほら、世の中にはこんなに気持ち悪い人たちが蔓延しているんです！みーんーな、晒し上げますよ！
Look, there are so many creepy people spreading through the world! I'm going to expose everyone!
触ったら逮捕！　極chu♡で点呼！
Touch and you're arrested! Roll call in prison!
いちー　にー　さん　しー
One, two, three, four
は？　ごめんなさいが聞こえなーい
Huh? I can't hear your apology
粛聖！　ロリ神レクイエム☆
Punishment! Loli-God Requiem☆
極chuにいる皆さーん、刑務所ファミリー！
Everyone in prison, prison family!
ファンサータイムのお時間でーす！
It's fan service time!
その腐り切った耳をゴリゴリカッポジってよーく聴いてくださいね。
Scrape out those rotten ears of yours and listen up closely.
ざぁーこ
Loser.
キモキモ
Gross, gross.
うるさい
Shut up.
黙ってもらっていいですか？
Could you just stay quiet?
嫌いです
I hate you.
かわいそ
How pitiful.
段差弱いみっともな～い！
Weak and pathetic!
どうしようもないお兄ちゃんお姉ちゃん
Good-for-nothing big brothers and sisters,
もう希望もないゴミだおめーら
you're all hopeless pieces of trash.
汚物消毒110番
Sanitize the filth, call 110!
固有結界発動
Inherent Domain, activate!
粛聖！おかビーム！
Punishment! Oka-Beam!
もういっちょ！しぐビーム！
One more! Shigu-Beam!
まだまだ！あみゃビーム！
Not done yet! Amya-Beam!
怒りの日。聖なるインターネットに血の雨が降り注いだ日。
Day of wrath. The day a rain of blood poured over the sacred internet.
愚かなロリコンを骨の髄まで浄化する。
Purifying foolish lolicons to the marrow of their bones.
一筋の光。それがおかビームなのである。
A single ray of light. That is the Oka-Beam.
あみゃは全てを許します…
Amya forgives everything...
嗚呼…この世の醜さを
Ah... the ugliness of this world,
集めて描いてみるよ
I'll gather it and try to draw it.
真っ白なキャンバスが
The pure white canvas
穢れて泣いている
is stained and crying.
Lonely振り向いた少女は
Lonely, the girl who turned around
そっと手を掴む…
softly grabs a hand...
楽園などないから
Because there is no paradise.
おっきなお友達のみんな
All you big friends out there,
お前らが打ち込んでいる虚無には
what meaning is there in the void
何の意味があるの？
that you are typing away at?
ねえ、教えてよ。ぼくぜんぜーんわかんないんだ！
Hey, tell me. I don't understand at all!
ロリロリ神降臨！
Loli-loli god descent!
さよなら笑顔でバイバイ！
Goodbye, with a smile, bye-bye!
ピリオドをどうぞ
Please, take your period,
この手で押してあげゆ
I'll press it for you with this hand.
ラブリーロリロリ神降臨！
Lovely loli-loli god descent!
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
If I ring the bell, it's just like this.
とても優しくて
A very kind
素敵なお兄ちゃん
and wonderful big brother.
楽園でほら
Look, in paradise,
ねんねしな
go to sleep now.
それが救済の
That is the requiem
レクイエム
of salvation.
せーの！触ったら逮捕！
Ready! Touching is an arrest!
獄中で点呼！
Roll call in prison!
いちにーさんしー？
One, two, three, four?
はぁ？はぁ？ごめんなさいが聞こえなーい！
Huh? Huh? I can't hear your apology!
粛聖！ロリ神レクイエム☆
Punishment! Loli-God Requiem☆
ほんっとーに、きもちわるい。
Honestly, you're disgusting.
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
嬉しすぎる…ありがとう…
I'm so happy... thank you...
どうしたの…やめて…
What's wrong? Stop...
御祝儀…ありがとう…初めましてあみゃちゃん。
A congratulatory gift... thank you... nice to meet you, Amya-chan.
あみゃちゃんです…あみゃちゃん…
I'm Amya... Amya...
どういう状況やこれ？
What kind of situation is this?
や、知ってるでしょう、ぼくがあみゃのオタクなの…もうだい…
No, you know, right? I'm an Amya otaku... it's just...
…こうなっちゃうんだ…こうなっちゃう…本当に可愛すぎて…
...I end up like this... like this... she's really too cute...
もう何かライブに呼べるってなって…もうどうしよう…
Somehow I was able to invite her to the live... what should I do...
何か権力使っちゃってるや！
You're totally using your power!
あぁ…嬉しい…ありがとう…可愛すぎる…どうしよう…
Ah... I'm so happy... thank you... you're too cute... what do I do...
なら…じゃあ写真でも撮ります？
Then... shall we take a photo?
えぇ！？いいのかな？撮っちゃっていいのかな？
Eh!? Is it okay? Can I really take it?
や、二人で撮ります？
No, you two want to take it?
いえいえ、三人で撮ろうよ。
No no, let's take it as a trio.
いいですか？せめてもらって…
Is it okay? Let's get closer...
じゃあやっぱりシンプルにね、ピースとかはどうですか？
Then, let's keep it simple, how about a peace sign?
はいチーズ！
Ready, cheese!
可愛い～！
So cute~!
え…あとどうしようかな…やりたいことない？
Eh... what else should we do... anything you want to do?
贅沢すぎる…何でもやる！何でもやる！何でも…！
Too luxurious... I'll do anything! I'll do anything! Anything...!
何でもはやめとこ。
Let's stop at 'anything'.
危ないから。
Because it's dangerous.
やばい奴なんだ。
She's a crazy person.
この後ろのモニターのイラストを再現するのはどう？
How about recreating the illustration on the monitor behind us?
あぁ、いいねこれ。
Ah, that's good.
こうかな？あみゃは？あみゃちゃんがこう…
Like this? How about Amya? Amya-chan is like this...
可愛い～！
So cute~!
椎名さんも、もっと何か…ゴミを、ゴミを見るような目で、椎名さんも。
Shiina-san too, more like... with eyes looking at trash, Shiina-san too.
そういうシチュエーション関係？変なことさせないで本当に。
Is that the kind of situation? Don't make me do weird things, seriously.
あぁ可愛い可愛い…いいね…可愛い…
Ah, cute, cute... nice... cute...
あと一個ぼくやりたいことあるんですけど、いいですか？
I have one more thing I want to do, is it okay?
何だ？
What is it?
椎名さんとあみゃちゃんでハート…
A heart with Shiina-san and Amya-chan...
興奮しすぎて…はぁ…はぁ…息切れしちゃってるよ。
I'm too excited... *pant* *pant*... I'm out of breath.
椎名さんとあみゃちゃんでハート作ってもらっていいですか？
Can I have Shiina-san and Amya-chan make a heart?
こう？そう…可愛い！
Like this? Yeah... cute!
そこにちょっと失礼して…さぁ！
Let me just squeeze in there... there!
幸せ…あぁ良かったです。
Happiness... ah, that was great.
いいね…ラブラブ…
Nice... lovey-dovey...
満足…満足…
Satisfied... satisfied...
（笑い声とざわつき）
(Laughter and chatter)
いや、本当に疲れた。
Man, I'm really tired.
今日ね、あの、あみゃちゃんに…
So today, I was going to ask Amya-chan...
自前のあみゃちゃんのアクリルスタンド持ってきて、サインしてもらおうかなって思ったんだけど、
to sign the Amya-chan acrylic stand I brought from home,
シオンさんがさっき言ったように、ちょっとね、権力使いすぎかなって思って…
but like Shion-san said earlier, I thought maybe that's abusing my power a bit...
権力（笑）
Power? (laughs)
やめてよ（笑）
Stop it! (laughs)
やめといたんだよ、あみゃちゃん。
So I held back, Amya-chan.
え、そんなことないよ！いくらでも書く！
Wait, that's not true! I'll sign as much as you want!
いくらでも書くって…いる？
"As much as you want"... but do you need it?
いる！いるよ！めちゃめちゃいるよ！
I do! I do! Tons of people want it!
しーが代わりに、いつでも、私のもいつでも書いてあげる！
I'll sign mine for you instead, anytime!
いる？
Do we need it?
え、いらない反応…
Wait, that "no thank you" reaction...
シオンさんもね、今日、ロリ初めてやってみたと思うんだけど、どうだったの？
Shion-san, I think today was your first time doing the "loli" style, how was it?
ロリね…
The loli thing...
めちゃめちゃ頑張った、無理した、ちょっと。
I worked really hard at it, I pushed myself a bit.
いや、可愛かったよ！めっちゃ可愛かった！
No, you were cute! So cute!
新たな扉を開いた、開いた、開いた。
A new door has been opened, opened, opened.
慣れてたか？
Were you used to it?
いや、ロリシオンめちゃめちゃ良かった。
Man, Loli Shion was amazing.
可愛かった？なんかね、強制的にロリにさせられて…
Was it cute? I was kind of forced into being a loli...
え？怖いよ、本当に（笑）
Eh? That's scary, seriously. (laughs)
いや、もう危ないから帰りましょう、危ないから。
It's getting dangerous, so let's head home. It's dangerous.
危ない？帰りましょう？おめでとうね！
Dangerous? Head home? Congratulations anyway!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
マジで可愛かったね。
They were seriously cute.
本当に、あのにじさんじのファンの方もたくさん見てるかと思うんですけど、あの本当に…
I think many Nijisanji fans are watching too, but truly...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
スマイルあげない / 作詞・作曲：ケンモチヒデフミ/あの
Smile Agenai / Lyrics & Composition: Kenmochi Hidefumi / Ano
お昼にテレビ みんなで食べた
Watching TV at lunch, we all ate
あのポテト
Those French fries
この部屋から 動けなくなって
Now I can't leave this room
現実逃避
Escaping reality
バンズ パティ マスタード
Buns, patty, mustard
ケチャップ チーズ いってらっしゃい
Ketchup, cheese, here you go
朝 早起きのご褒美
A reward for waking up early
片手にいってらっしゃい
With it in one hand, off you go
ギリギリ生きてる毎日
Barely making it through each day
怒られたら残機減る
Remaining lives drop when I'm scolded
出来ること褒めてくれたら
If you praise what I can do
1UP
僕はニコとスマイルあげないぜ
I won't give you a cheeky smile
僕は僕のままのキャラクターで
I'll stay as my own character
世界をジュワッと揚げちゃうぜ
I'll fry up the world until it's juicy
そこへ僕は塩を振る
And then I'll sprinkle some salt
僕はニコとスマイルあげないぜ
I won't give you a cheeky smile
手っ取り早くこなす お茶の子さいさいさ
Handling things quickly, a total piece of cake
やっぱ足りてない協調性だけど
I'm still lacking in cooperativeness
僕は指揮を振る
But I'll lead the way
ルールも知らずに突っ込んでく
Diving in without knowing the rules
プレイヤー
Player
死なないためのマニュアルなきゃ
Without a manual to stay alive
ゲームオーバー
Game Over
人とコミュニケーションは難しい
Communication is hard
だけど出来そうな気がする テレパシー
But I feel like I could do it with telepathy
作業にハマれば 意外と楽しい
It's surprisingly fun when I get into a task
そして褒めてもらえたら ちょっと嬉しい
And if you praise me, I'm a little happy
チキン チキン ナゲ ナゲ バーベ バーベキュー
Chicken chicken nugge nugge barbe barbeque
チキン チキン ナゲ ナゲ マスタード
Chicken chicken nugge nugge mustard
ハッピー ハッピー セットにはお宝
Happy happy, there's a treasure in the meal set
ピクルス抜きにも カスタマイズ
Customized it even without pickles
ギリギリ生きてる毎日
Barely making it through each day
怒られたら残機減る
Remaining lives drop when I'm scolded
出来ること褒めてくれたら
If you praise what I can do
1UP
僕はニコとスマイルあげないぜ
I won't give you a cheeky smile
僕は僕のままのキャラクターで
I'll stay as my own character
世界をジュワッと揚げちゃうぜ
I'll fry up the world until it's juicy
そこへ僕は塩を振る
And then I'll sprinkle some salt
僕はニコとスマイルあげないぜ
I won't give you a cheeky smile
手っ取り早くこなす お茶の子さいさいさ
Handling things quickly, a total piece of cake
やっぱ足りてない協調性だけど
I'm still lacking in cooperativeness
僕は指揮を振る
But I'll lead the way
いつかニコと素直になれますか
Will I ever be able to smile honestly?
今はスマイルあげられない
Right now, I can't give you a smile
せーの！
One, two!
は！
Ha!
アムアムアムアム...
Munch, munch, munch, munch...
はぁー...
Sigh...
ライブ中なのに、
Even though I'm in the middle of a live...
眠くなってきちゃったー...
I've started to feel sleepy...
グー...
Zzz...
おばけのウケねらい
作詞・作曲：ピノキオピー
Obake no Uke-nerai
Lyrics & Composition: PinocchioP
それ本気でやってんの
Are you doing that for real?
ねえおばけを舐めてんの
Hey, are you underestimating ghosts?
また枕元立ってんの
Standing by the bedside again?
もう何回やってんの
How many times have you done that?
ほら、怖がれという態度
Look, an attitude of "be afraid"
怖がって欲しいという展望
A prospect of wanting to be feared
あなたはどっちかな？
Which one are you?
神はおっしゃるどっちでもいい
God says either is fine
心霊写真はウケねらい
Spirit photography is for laughs
誰でもわかるウケねらい
Obvious laughs for anyone
渋い呪いもウケねらい
Even a bitter curse is for laughs
玄人に向けたウケねらい
Laughs aimed at experts
てっとりばやく恐怖与えたい
I want to give a quick scare
日進月歩恐怖磨きたい
I want to polish the fear day by day
よそはよそ　うちはうち
What's theirs is theirs, what's ours is ours
鬼は外から福は内
Demons out, luck in
自分がない自分がないから浮かばれない
No self, because there's no self, I can't find peace
持論がある持論があるから報われたい
Have a theory, because I have a theory, I want to be rewarded
流行りに乗ってるけど好きでやってんのね
Riding the trend, but doing it because I like it, right?
それとも魂売って自分殺してんの
Or are you selling your soul and killing yourself?
ひゅーどろろ　ひゅーどろろ
Hyu-dororo, hyu-dororo
滑ってるのにみんなは称賛
Even though it's failing, everyone praises it
日々労働をのち法要を
Daily labor followed by a memorial service
続けけます　わたしの好きなウケねらいを
I'll continue my favorite "trying for laughs"
じんわり火が灯る
ローソク吹き消し
A fire slowly lights up,
blow out the candle
大音量のラップ音で
すべてが台無し
With the loud volume of rapping sounds,
everything is ruined
ありがち？いやスタンダード
斬新？いや出オチ
Common? No, standard
Innovative? No, a punchline from the start
心霊スポットのレビュー
怨念の考察
Reviews of haunted spots,
analysis of grudges
その方法は受け入れない
胡散臭いから受け入れない
I don't accept that method,
because it's fishy
その発想は受け入れたい
不器用だけど受け入れたい
I want to accept that idea,
even if it's clumsy
効率よくテキトーに化けたい
損するけどディテール詰めたい
I want to transform efficiently and carelessly,
I'll lose out, but I want to nail the details
よそはよそ　うちはうち
What's theirs is theirs, what's ours is ours
大体は絵に描いた餅
Mostly just pie in the sky
事件がない事件がないからリアルじゃない
No incidents, because there are no incidents, it's not real
危険がある危険があるからみんなは期待
There's danger, because there's danger, everyone expects it
悪霊のイッてる感じわざと出してんのね
You're putting on that "crazy evil spirit" vibe on purpose, aren't you?
それとも魂売って自分殺してんの
Or are you selling your soul and killing yourself?
ひゅーどろろ　ひゅーどろろ
Hyu-dororo, hyu-dororo
嗤ってたのにあえなく降参
Even though I was sneering, I surrendered helplessly
意気揚々と死後ひょうひょうと
Triumphantly, and after death, nonchalantly
わかってるのにやめられぬウケねらいよ
Even though I know it, I can't stop trying for laughs
生前から引いてばっかりの外れくじ
A losing ticket I've been drawing since before I was born
好きだったおばけはどっか行って神隠し
The ghost I liked went somewhere, spirited away
やったもん勝ちの許せるラインがぼやけだし
The line of what's allowed in "winner takes all" is blurring
大嫌いなオカルトをみんなが好きでもそういうもんだし
Even if everyone likes the occult I hate, that's just how it is
自分がない自分がないから浮かばれない
No self, because there's no self, I can't find peace
持論がある持論があるから報われたい
Have a theory, because I have a theory, I want to be rewarded
流行りに乗ってるけど好きでやってんのね
Riding the trend, but doing it because I like it, right?
それとも魂売って自分殺してんの
Or are you selling your soul and killing yourself?
ひゅーどろろ　ひゅーどろろ
Hyu-dororo, hyu-dororo
滑ってるのにみんなは称賛
Even though it's failing, everyone praises it
ひゅーどろろ　ひゅーどろろ
Hyu-dororo, hyu-dororo
嗤ってたのにあえなく降参
Even though I was sneering, I surrendered helplessly
ひゅーどろろ　ひゅーどろろ
Hyu-dororo, hyu-dororo
日々労働をのち法要を
Daily labor followed by a memorial service
意気揚々と死後ひょうひょうと
Triumphantly, and after death, nonchalantly
続けけます　わたしの好きなウケねらいを
I'll continue my favorite "trying for laughs"
ばぁ〜
Baa~
あー、もうやめやめやめ！
やめてやめてやめてー！
Ah, enough, enough, enough!
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
というわけで突然ですが...
And so, suddenly...
ゲマズバラエティコーナー！
Gamers Variety Corner!
お前ら本当に地獄好きだな編ー！
The "You guys really love hell" Edition!
イエーイ！
Yay!
別に好きじゃないが！
We don't really like it, though!
ということで改めて
So, once again,
このステージがどういう作りかと言うと
to explain how this stage works,
サバイバルエリア内でオチのある話をすると
if you tell a story with a punchline in the survival area,
床が落ちるという仕組みとなってまーす
the floor will drop.
おお～
Ohh~
そんな簡単に落ちんやろうて
I doubt it'll drop that easily.
まあね、まあそんな簡単には
Well, yeah, it won't drop
落ちないですよねえ、フブキさん
that easily, right, Fubuki-san?
どこ行くの、ミオ
Where are you going, Mio?
どこ行くの、ミオちゃん
Where are you going, Mio-chan?
えい！
Ei!
うわああああ！！！
Uwaaaaa!!!
フブにゃん！？
Fubu-nyan!?
落ちたあ～！！
I fell~!!
なんでテストで落としたの！
Why did you drop me during the test?!
はい、というわけでね
All right, well,
この後のLIVEパートに盛り上げて繋げる為にも
to get hyped up for the Live part coming up,
精一杯オチをつけて皆さん頑張ってくださいね
everyone, do your best to deliver punchlines!
一回落ちてしまった人はオチをつけるまで残ってもらいますからね
Anyone who falls has to stay down there until they land a punchline.
地獄だ、本当に
This is hell, seriously.
やめてくれ
Please stop.
まず最初のお題はこちら！
First prompt is this!
YAGOOがギリギリ言わなそうなセリフ
A line YAGOO is just barely unlikely to say
A line YAGOO is just barely unlikely to say.
はい！ころね！
Yes! Korone!
まだいたんですか
Are you still here?
ギリ言わなそう～
He'd barely not say that~
ころね落ちた～！！
Korone fell~!!
やった～！！やったよ～！！
Yay!! I did it~!!
はいはいはい！これ自信あります
Yes, yes, yes! I'm confident in this one.
ミオさん...はみ出てます
Mio-san... it's sticking out.
何がですか…？今ウケてたのに～
What is...? I was just starting to get it~
おかゆんの手前に入れる感じで
Like, right before Okayun's...
ミオさん、はみ出てます
Mio-san, it's sticking out.
はい次のお題いきま～す！
Okay, next prompt!
なんでえええ～！！！
Whyyyy~!!!
はい、というわけで次のお題はこちらです
Okay, so the next prompt is this.
白上フブキ「赤いなぁ」何を見て言った？
Shirakami Fubuki said "It's red, isn't it." What was she looking at?
白上フブキ「赤いなぁ」何を見て言った？シンキングタイムスタート！
Shirakami Fubuki said "It's red, isn't it." What was she looking at? Thinking time, start!
はい！白上さん！
Yes! Shirakami-san!
ミオのパンツ
Mio's panties.
白上どーん！！やったああ～！！
Shirakami, BAM!! Yaaaay~!!
あっ分かった！！背中に違和感あるなあ...
Ah, I got it!! My back feels weird...
あ、かい～な
Ah, it's itchy.
おかゆ、おめでと～！！やった～！！
Okayu, congrats~!! Yay~!!
9999億円かけて新スタジオが設立！衝撃の設備とは？
A new studio was established with 999.9 billion yen! What is its shocking equipment?
9999億円かけて新スタジオが設立！衝撃の設備とは？シンキングタイムスタート！
A new studio was established with 999.9 billion yen! What is its shocking equipment? Thinking time, start!
はい白上！
Yes, Shirakami!
メカYAGOOがお茶運んでくれる
Mecha YAGOO serves tea.
よく見るよね飲食店で。メカYAGOO採用～
You see that often in restaurants. Mecha YAGOO is accepted!
はい！ころね！
Yes! Korone!
政府
Government.
政府の人がいるってこと？
Like, government people... are there?
シュールですね...はいは～い！おかゆん！
That's surreal... Yes, yes! Okayun!
みんなに僕たちのニオイが伝わる
Everyone can smell our scent.
えええ～！！すごい設備～！！みんな欲しいよねえ？
Eeeeh!! Amazing equipment~!! Everyone wants that, right?
はいころね！
Yes, Korone!
多分それは何かのまちがい
That's probably some kind of mistake.
お金そんなかけられないから
They can't spend that much money.
リアリストですねえ。落とせえ～！！
You're a realist. Drop her~!!
写真で一言!!
One word for the photo!!
写真で一言！！ということでその写真見てみましょう、どうぞ！
One word for the photo!! Let's take a look at the photo, please!
おお～！かわいい～！！こちらの写真を見て一言お願いしま～す！
Oh~! So cute~!! Please give us one word for this photo!
奥の方には薪が置いてあったりとかしてますね
There's some firewood piled up in the back.
はいころねさん！
Yes, Korone-san!
ま～きの！
Ma~kino!
待って、それで言うとこっちもあるんじゃね。後ろの薪も兼ねてるからね。オッケー！はい！
Wait, if you say that, there's this one too. It includes the firewood in the back. Okay! Yes!
おいお前...
Hey, you...
さっき俺と薪間違えて燃やしただろ
You accidentally burned me instead of the firewood earlier, didn't you?
焦げてるでしょ！？わあああ～！！
You're scorched, right!? Waaaaa~!!
かわいそうだからやめてください！そういうかわいいの出てこないよ～！
Please stop, he's pitiful! I can't come up with anything cute like that!
精一杯考えたのがこれだったよ。はい精一杯考えた白上さんの答えどうぞ！
This was the best I could think of. Okay, here's Shirakami-san's hard-earned answer!
ゆーちゅーばーの方ですか？
Are you a YouTuber?
77ちゃん 可愛い❤️
77-chan is cute❤️
落としてくれよぉぉ～！！
Let me fall!!
ではお次の行きましょうかね、大喜利の題。こちら。
Now, let's move on to the next Oogiri theme. Here it is.
皆さん、ケモ耳を3回撫でられると何かが起こるらしいですね？
Everyone, it seems like something happens when you pet animal ears 3 times, right?
何かが起こる...
Something happens...
はい！
Yes!
おっ、早い。おかゆさん。
Oh, that was fast. Okayu-san.
やめろぉぉ～ 「〇口」はやめろぉね～
Stop it~~ Stop the "〇 mouth"~~
ミオちゃん好きだと思ったのにぃ。ダメだよぉ。
I thought you liked me, Mio-chan. No good.
白上さん。
Shirakami-san.
〇リ
〇ri
離れてくれぇぇ！！
Get away from me!!
〇っこ
〇kko
やめてぇぇぇ！！
Stop it!!
ダメだって。さっきの流れで、はい。
No way. Following the previous flow, yes.
〇リと〇口 ねえぇぇ～ｗ
〇ri and 〇 mouth. Hey~~ lol
やめて！グリとグラみたいに言うな！
Stop! Don't say it like Guri and Gura!
じゃあうちが実際に撫でてみて、どういう気持ちになるか。なるほど。
Then, I'll actually try petting them and see how it feels. I see.
わしゃわしゃ... わしゃ。どうでしょう？
Petting... Washu. How is it?
気持ちいい、普通に。
It feels good, normally.
ダメだｗ もうだめだ、気持ちよくなっちゃったｗ
No good lol It's over, she started feeling too good lol
わしゃわしゃ... わしゃ、ミオちゃん気持ちいい...
Petting... Washu, Mio-chan feels good...
吐き気
Nausea
デッ！ｗｗ この流れで？ｗｗ
Geh! lol In this flow? lol
ダメだ。
No good.
わしゃわしゃ... わしゃ...
Petting... Washu...
願いを一つだけ叶えてやろう...
I shall grant you one wish...
魔神さん？ｗ めっちゃおもろいやんｗｗ
A Genie? lol That's so funny lol
やったあぁぁ～！！
Yay~~!!
これね、ランプじゃなくて、多分なんかこういうカレールーに入ってそうだなって思っちゃったｗ
This, it's not a lamp, I just thought it looked like it'd be in something like curry roux lol
思いつかないんだよぉ～...
I can't think of anything~~...
絶対退会だ。
Definitely retiring.
お前ら本当に地獄が好きな編ということで、本当にそういう感じになりましたけど、いかがでしたか？
The "You guys really love hell" edition, and it really turned out that way, but how was it?
おもしろかったあ～
It was fun~
勝ち猫になってますねｗ
You've become a winning cat lol
じゃあ最後のお題ということで！うちも特別に参加しちゃおうと思いま～す！おーい！
Then, for the last theme! I'm going to specially join in too! Oh!
それでは、今から4人で歌う歌は何でしょうか？
Now, what is the song the four of us are about to sing?
これはさすがにわかるんじゃないか？
That, you'd know for sure, right?
大喜利じゃないからね...？
It's not an Oogiri, okay...?
めっちゃ念押すじゃん。
You're really emphasizing that.
できたぁ！
Done!
それでは皆さん、一斉に出しましょう。せ～の！！
Then everyone, let's show them all at once. Ready, go!!
ア イ ド ル
I D O L
というわけで！みんなこれから行くよ！アイドルのポーズ！せ～の！はい！
And so! Everyone, here we go! Idol pose! Ready, go! Yes!
アイドルのポーズこんなんじゃねぇだろぉぉ～！！
That's not what an idol pose is like!!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
A media storm with an invincible smile
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Mysterious, wanting to know that secret
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her flaws are part of her area
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You, perfect and a liar
天才的なアイドル様
The genius idol-sama
今日何食べた？ 好きな本は？ 遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
What did you eat today? Favorite book? Where do you go out?
何も食べてない
I haven't eaten anything
それは内緒
That's a secret
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
No matter what I'm asked, I'm elusive
そう淡々とだけど燦々と
So coolly, yet so brilliantly
見えそうで見えない蜜は蜜の味
The honey that's almost visible but not, is the taste of honey
あれもないないない これもないないない
None of that, none of this
好きなタイプは？ 相手は？
What's your type? Who's the partner?
さあ答えて
Come on, answer
「誰かを好きになることなんて 私分からなくてさ」
"Falling in love with someone, I just don't understand it."
嘘か本当か知り得ない
I can't tell if it's a lie or the truth
そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
By those words, another person falls
また好きにさせる また好きにさせる
Making them love me again, making them love me again
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone is being captivated
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
You are the perfect and ultimate idol
金輪際現れない
Never to appear again
一番星の生まれ変わり
The reincarnation of the brightest star
その笑顔で愛してるで誰も彼も虜にしていく
With that smile, with "I love you," making everyone your captive
誰しもが瞳がその言葉が嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
Everyone's eyes, those words, even if they're lies, that's perfect Love
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, yes, that girl is special
我々はハナからおまけです
We're just extras from the start
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're the supporting cast B for the star
全てが全てもあの子のおかげなわけない
It's not all thanks to that girl
洒落臭い妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
Nasty envy and jealousy, there's no way it's not there
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
This isn't a joke, that's why it's unforgivable
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない自分を許せない 誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
Not perfect, can't forgive you, can't forgive myself, I won't acknowledge anyone but you
誰もが信じ崇めてる まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Everyone believes and worships, truly the strongest and invincible idol
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses to be found
一番星を宿してる
Carrying the brightest star
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
You can't show any weaknesses, no, no
知りたくないとこは見せずに
Without showing parts people don't want to know
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
It has to be one and only, or I hate it
それこそ本物のアイ
That's exactly what real Love is
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Captivating the media with a signature smile
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
Keeping this secret strictly under wraps
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
A career built on the lie of "I love you"
これこそ私なりの愛だ
This is my own kind of love
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even the beads of sweat are like beautiful aqua
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
Within these eyelids, rubies are hidden
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing and dancing, I am Maria
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lies are the ultimate form of love
誰かに愛されたことも
Never having been loved by anyone
誰かのこと愛したこともない
And never having loved anyone either
そんな私の嘘が
Hoping that my lies
いつか本当になること
Will one day come true
信じてる
I believe
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
One day, I'll surely have it all
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I am such a greedy idol
等身大でみんなのこと
Wanting to love everyone
ちゃんと愛したいから
Wholeheartedly, just as I am
今日も嘘をつくの
So I'll keep telling lies today
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
Praying for the day these words finally become the truth
それでもまだ
But even so
君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
I still couldn't say it to you, or you...
やっと言えた
Finally, I said it
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is absolutely not a lie
愛してる
I love you
はい！ということでゲマズでアイドルを歌わせてもらいましたー！
Alright! So, the Gamers performed "Idol" together!
イエーイ！
Yay!
可愛かったでしょー！
We were cute, right?!
なんかさっきまであんな大喜利してたとは思えないようなガチの歌い方だったよね
I can't believe we were just doing comedy bits with that kind of serious singing.
そうなんだよねー
Exactly.
ま、でもま、こういうギャップがゲマズのいいところでもありますからな
Well, but that kind of gap is what's great about the Gamers.
そうだよね！ゲマズ最高！イエーイ！
Right! Gamers are the best! Yay!
あ！そうだ、おかゆ！
Ah! That's right, Okayu!
ん？
Hmm?
お誕生日おめでとー！
Happy Birthday!
おめでとうー！！
Congratulations!!
ちょっとさっきもね、ドロけんでお祝いしてもらったのにもう2回もお祝いしてもらっちゃったよ
I just got celebrated by Doroken earlier, and now I'm being celebrated a second time.
いやもう何回でもお祝いするよ。おめでとう！
No, we'll celebrate as many times as it takes. Congratulations!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
待ってみんな！
Wait, everyone!
はぁ、はぁ、はぁ...おおー！着替えてきましたー！
Ha, ha, ha... Oh! I've changed my outfit!
ゲマズのみんなもう行っちゃった...。でもさ、でもさ！
Everyone from the Gamers has already left... But you know, but you know!
今年はゲマズ、年始まってからもコラボしてるし、今年結構ゲマズイヤーになるんじゃなーい？
The Gamers have been doing collabs since the start of the year, so don't you think this might be a real Gamers Year?
なんかそんな予感してるよ！僕めっちゃ楽しみ！
I have a feeling it will be! I'm so excited!
え？
Eh?
えっ？
What?
いやいやいや、お前じゃお前じゃ！待って、オカニャン？！
No, no, no, it's you, it's you! Wait, Okanyan?!
なんでいるの？！えっ、え、でもさ、オカニャンってさ...
Why are you here?! Wait, but you know, Okanyan...
3Dの体あったっけ？なかったよね。これもしや...
Did you have a 3D body? You didn't, right. Could this be...
初めて？！オカニャン3D初配信ってこと？！
The first time?! Does this mean it's Okanyan's 3D debut stream?!
うわ、グーしてるグーしてる。あははは！
Wow, he's giving a thumbs up. Hahaha!
え、オカニャンってこんなに大きかったんだ...
Eh, I didn't know Okanyan was this big...
うわー、何この生々しいカメラ。オカニャンには全然必要ないからね。
Wow, look at this realistic camera work. Okanyan doesn't need that at all.
えー、じゃあせっかく来てくれてるし、オカニャンと一緒に写真でも撮る？
Well then, since you're here, should we take a picture together, Okanyan?
あ、わかった。じゃあなんか無難にピースでもやる？
Oh, okay. Then should we just do a simple peace sign?
はい、チーズ！
Say cheese!
デカいな...
He's huge...
なんか足も長いし...。ちょっとスタイリッシュなポーズもやってみる？
And his legs are so long... Shall we try a more stylish pose?
あ、それね。こうかな？
Oh, that one. Like this?
いやいやいや、これ誰がどんな風にいつ使う素材になっちゃうんだろう。
No, no, no, I wonder who will use this material, and when and how.
でもね、あのXの人たちってこういうの好きなんんじゃないかな。うんうん。
But you know, I think people on X might like this kind of thing. Yeah, yeah.
オカニャン、お？オカニャンどうしたの？
Okanyan, oh? What is it, Okanyan?
ふんふん...ふんふん。
Hmm-hmm... I see.
あー、なるほど！
Ah, I see!
オカニャンは実は今日、僕のオリジナル曲の発表があって、そのお祝いに来てくれたんだって！
Okanyan actually came here to celebrate because I'm announcing my new original song today!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
じゃあオカニャンと一緒に新曲、踊っていきたいと思います！
Then, I'd like to dance to my new song together with Okanyan!
では楽曲発表、いきます！
Now, here is the song announcement!
新曲は『ネコカブリーナ』！いくよオカニャン！
The new song is "Nekokaburiina"! Let's go, Okanyan!
生の 本音は えぐいから
Since raw true intentions are gruesome,
ちゃんと火を通して食べてね
make sure to cook them thoroughly before eating.
リップサービスはズルいかな？
Is lip service cheating?
それも以心伝心のレシピ
That's also a recipe for heart-to-heart communication.
みんな〜 自分 偽ってるかい？
Everyone~ are you faking yourself?
嘘の万国博覧会
An international exposition of lies.
みんな〜 自分 偽ってるかい？
Everyone~ are you faking yourself?
痛みを飼いならして
Taming the pain.
シャー
Hiss!
嫌いだけどスキ 拙くてもいい
I hate it but I like it, it's fine even if it's clumsy.
着ぐるみを着てハグしてあげる
I'll wear a costume and give you a hug.
泣かせないように 怒らせないように
So as not to make you cry, so as not to make you angry.
丁度良く君と遊びたいのだ
I want to play with you just the right amount.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Nekokaburīna, Nekokaburīna.
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like the slightly timid you.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Nekokaburīna, Nekokaburīna.
取り繕ってる ぼくが好き？
Do you like me when I'm putting on appearances?
弱さを知ってる 君が好きだよ
I like you, who knows weakness.
思うと言うとでは大違い
There's a big difference between thinking and saying.
建前も用法と用量次第
Facade depends on usage and dosage.
みんな〜 自分 偽ってるかい？
Everyone~ are you faking yourself?
ひとりぼっちの音楽隊
A lonely musical band.
みんな〜 自分 偽ってるかい？
Everyone~ are you faking yourself?
首輪の鈴 鳴らして
Ring the bell on your collar.
フギャー
Meow!
災難だけどハッピー しんどくても平気
It's a disaster but I'm happy, it's tough but I'm fine.
あべこべな夢を見せてあげる
I'll show you a topsy-turvy dream.
傷つかないように 追い詰めないように
So you won't get hurt, so you won't be cornered.
夜明けまで君とふざけあうのだ
I'll fool around with you until dawn.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Nekokaburīna, Nekokaburīna.
爪を丸めてる君が好き
I like the you with your claws rounded.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Nekokaburīna, Nekokaburīna.
涙を見せない ぼくが好き？
Do you like me when I don't show tears?
痛みを知ってる 君が好きだよ
I like you, who knows pain.
君は猫 猫 ファスナーつきの猫
You are a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper.
君は人 人 ファスナーつきの人
You are a person, a person, a person with a zipper.
あれはUFO UFO ファスナーつきのUFO
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper.
君は猫 猫 ファスナーつきの猫
You are a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper.
君は人 人 ファスナーつきの人
You are a person, a person, a person with a zipper.
あれはUFO UFO ファスナーつきのUFO
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper.
君は誰？ 誰？ 特別な人
Who are you? Who? A special person.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Nekokaburīna, Nekokaburīna.
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like the slightly timid you.
君も ぼくも 馴染めない世界で
In a world where neither you nor I fit in,
やっと見つけた居場所だから
because it's the place I finally found.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Nekokaburīna, Nekokaburīna.
取り繕ってる ぼくが好き？
Do you like me when I'm putting on appearances?
君も ぼくも どうかしてる世界で
In a world where both you and I are crazy,
明日もまた会えたら良いな
I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Nekokaburīna, Nekokaburīna.
弱さを知ってる 君が好きだよ
I like you, who knows weakness.
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
僕の2024年3Dライブ、Cat Hoodie どうだったかな？
How was my 2024 3D live, "Cat Hoodie"?
楽しんで、笑えたかな？
Did you enjoy it and laugh?
後日、僕の配信でいろいろ裏話とか話せたらいいなって思うよ！
I hope to talk about various behind-the-scenes stories in my stream later!
みんな、まだ帰らないで！
Everyone, don't leave yet!
この後、重大な告知があるから！
Because there's a huge announcement after this!
またねー！
See ya!
はーい、みんな！生誕祭ライブ、楽しんでもらえたかな？
Hi, everyone! I hope you enjoyed the birthday celebration live!
今お披露目させていただいた僕の新オリジナル曲、「ネコカブリーナ」は、
My new original song "Nekokaburīna" that I just premiered...
この後、21時からプレミア公開されます！
...will have its MV premiere at 9:00 PM!
猫又おかゆ史上初めてのフルアニメーションMVとなりますので、
It's Nekomata Okayu's first-ever full animation MV...
みんなにいっぱい堪能してほしい！
...so I want everyone to enjoy it to the fullest!
楽曲は、「もぐもぐYUMMY」でもお馴染み、ピノキオピー様に書いていただきました！
The song was written by PinocchioP, who's also known for "Mogu Mogu YUMMY"!
可愛らしく、何度も何度も聞きたくなること間違いなし！
It's cute, and no doubt you'll want to hear it again and again!
この後、24時から各種音楽サイトでも配信がありますよ！
It'll also be available on various music sites starting at midnight!
続いての告知です！
Next announcement!
なんと！全国のアミューズメント施設で稼働中のサウンドボルテックスと僕のコラボが開催中！
A collaboration between me and Sound Voltex, currently in arcades nationwide, is underway!
わーい！
Yay!
僕がネメシスクルーとしておにぎりゃーたちをボイス付きでサポートしちゃうよ！
I'll be supporting the Onigiri-yas as a Nemesis Crew member with my voice!
詳細はこちら！
Details are here!
期間限定で猫又おかゆプレミアムジェネレーターが登場！
Nekomata Okayu Premium Generator is available for a limited time!
ボイス付きアピールスタンプ、ホログラの名シーンや、僕のMV...
Voice appeal stamps, famous scenes from HoloGra, my MVs...
ムービーが見られるムービー壁紙などの豪華コラボアイテムもゲットできちゃうんだ。
You can also get luxurious collaboration items, like movie wallpapers where you can watch videos.
そして e-amusement pass カードプレゼントキャンペーンも開催中！
And the e-amusement pass card giveaway campaign is also underway!
SOUND VOLTEX のデータを保存するのに必要なカードを僕のデザインでゲットできちゃうよ。
You can get the card needed to save your SOUND VOLTEX data with my design!
さらに抽選で e-amusement pass カードが当たるキャンペーンも開催中！
Furthermore, a campaign where you can win an e-amusement pass card by lottery is also live!
SOUND VOLTEX 公式 X アカウントのチェックを忘れずにね。
Don't forget to check the official SOUND VOLTEX X account.
最後に『もぐもぐYUMMY!』『毒杯スワロウ』『神様ネコ様』の3曲が...
Finally, three songs: 'Mogu Mogu YUMMY!', 'Doku-hai Swallow', and 'Kami-sama Neko-sama'...
...SOUND VOLTEX に本日から収録！
...are added to SOUND VOLTEX starting today!
たくさんプレイしてほしいな。
I hope you play them a lot.
以上、SOUND VOLTEX の告知でした！
That's all for the SOUND VOLTEX announcements!
続いてはお楽しみ、新グッズのお知らせです。
Next up is the exciting part, the new merchandise announcement.
たくさんアイデアねりねりしたよ。
I brainstormed a lot of ideas.
まずはこちら、おかゆとおそろいパーカー！
First up is this, the 'Okayu Matching Hoodie'!
つっ、ついに皆さん待望であったであろう猫又おかゆパーカー！
At, at last! The Nekomata Okayu hoodie that I'm sure you've all been waiting for!
胸にスタイリッシュな角度のおにぎりがプリントされてるよ。
It has a stylishly angled rice ball printed on the chest.
ホロライブのイベントに着ていくもよし...
You can wear it to hololive events...
...飾って僕と一緒に生活してる感じを楽しむのもよし。
...or display it to feel like you're living with me.
運営さんと再現を目指すためにたくさん生地にもこだわりました。
The staff and I were very picky about the fabric to ensure it's a perfect replica.
続いて...
Next...
おにぎりゃーぬいぐるみ！
...the Onigiryaa plushie!
僕のぬいぐるみは結構出てるけど、やっぱりおにぎりゃーのぬいぐるみも欲しいよね。
There are quite a few plushies of me, but you definitely want an Onigiryaa one too, right?
今まで販売してたおかゆぬいぐるみと並べてみてもいい感じになるサイズにしてみたよ。
I made it a size that looks great next to the Okayu plushies we've sold before.
デスクや寝室、飾りたいとこに置ける自立型のぬいぐるみ。
It's a self-standing plushie you can put on your desk, in your bedroom, or anywhere you want.
支えがなくても座ってくれる、ぜひ僕のぬいと一緒に並べてみてね。
It sits on its own without support, so please display it with my plushie.
続きましては、ついに奴がグッズ化します。
Moving on, 'that guy' is finally getting merchandise.
ドン！おかにゃんタンブラー！『WAIYADE』！
Bam! The Oka-nyan Tumbler! 'WAIYADE'!
なんと、ホロライブ史上初めてのおかにゃんグッズが登場だ！
Unbelievable! The very first Oka-nyan merchandise in hololive history is here!
おかにゃんファンの根強い希望によりグッズ化させていただきました。
We made this into merch due to the persistent requests from Oka-nyan fans.
家でもオフィスでも使いやすいように、シンプルかつ少し控えめに おかにゃんが君を応援してくれるよ。
Oka-nyan will cheer you on with a simple, subtle design that's easy to use at home or in the office.
メタリックカラーなオシャレタンブラーでやる気がみなぎる！
This stylish metallic tumbler will fill you with motivation!
お次は...
Next up...
『ネコカブリーナ』仕様のアクリルスタンド！
The 'Neko-ca-balina' version acrylic stand!
こちら、この後公開されるアニメMV仕様となっております。
This one is based on the animated MV that will be released after this.
今回のアニメMVでもキャラクターデザインを担当してくださった愛音望先生にイラスト原案をお願いしました。
We asked Aineno Nozomi-sensei, who did the character designs for the MV, to do the original illustration.
か、可愛すぎる...
I-it's too cute...
アニメMVオリジナルの衣装なので、まじまじと見てほしいな。
It's an original costume from the animated MV, so I want you to take a close look at it.
そして、最後はですね...
And finally...
ジャジャン！今回フルセット購入していただいた方には特典があります！
Tada! There's a bonus for those who purchase the full set!
直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドが付いてくるよ！
It comes with a hand-signed, polaroid-style card!
購入制限は無制限！
There's no purchase limit!
買ってくれた人みんなに僕のサインが届くよ。
Everyone who buys one will receive my autograph.
愛情たっぷりのサイン、書かせていただきます。
I'll be signing them with lots of love.
ということで、グッズのお知らせでした！みんなよかったらお迎えしてね。
So, that was the merchandise announcement! Please get them if you'd like.
ではこの後、最高のアニメMV『ネコカブリーナ』のプレミア公開をぜひみんな見に行ってみてね。
Now, please go watch the premiere of the awesome animated MV 'Neko-ca-balina' after this!
それではお疲れ様でした！完食！
Well then, thanks for your hard work! Finished the meal!
おかゆ〜！
Okayu~!